中歐
“五號礦井屠夫”受害者家屬譴責暴力
－他怎么了 －沒事
- What's wrong with him? - Nothing.
我們只是給他注射了鎮定劑
Just gave him something to calm him down.
等藥效過了呢 會有危險嗎
But when it wears off, he's not dangerous, is he?
－那就不歸我管了 －該死
- That's your problem now. - Fuck.
好吧 帶他進來
All right, bring him in.
快點 她要開始演講了
Come on. She's about to give her speech.
－你叫什么來著 下士 －祖巴克
What's your name again, Corporal? Zubak.
硬元音
Hard vowels.
像是要吐了
Regurgitative, that.
你的教名是什么
What's your Christian name?
－赫伯特 －赫伯特
- Herbert. - Herbert?
赫伯特祖巴克 念起來真拗口
Herbert Zubak, just trips off the tongue.
有點亂 你別介意
Pardon the mess.
都怪該死的建筑工
Fuckin' builders.
我可以把他們全殺了 你有什么建議嗎
Suppose I could just shoot them all if you have any tips.
你好 親愛的
Hello, my dear.
別擔心這股氨水味
Don't worry about the ammonia smell.
這是幾個月來第三次消毒了
They're sanitizing for the third time in as many months.
你以為這是看房日嗎
What the fuck you think this is? An open house?
快去樓下找你的建筑隊
Go and find your team downstairs.
可怕的高個女人是財政部長蘇珊戈恩
The tall, scary woman is Susan Goin, Minister of Finance.
毛茸茸的矮個男人 是首相的私人醫生 科肖醫生
The short, furry man is Dr. Kershaw the Chancellor's personal physician.
給他穿上外套
Put his jacket on.
天哪 他像一匹拉犁的馬
Christ, he's a plow horse.
這家伙撐不過一周
This one won't last a week.
好了 坐吧
Okay, sit.
好
All right.
你好
Hello in there.
能聽見嗎
Are you with us?
我先說清楚 我曾強烈反對選擇你
I should tell you I vehemently opposed your selection.
你用你開槍的手指給我們惹了大麻煩
You and your trigger finger made quite a fucking mess for us.
但是首相非要你來 所以就你了
But the Chancellor insisted, so... here you are.
－他簽字了吧 艾格尼絲 －是的 簽過了
And he's signed everything, has he, Agnes? Yeah, yeah, earlier.
很好
Good. Good!
我們從哪里開始呢
So, where to begin?
濕氣怎么樣
I suppose... moisture, yes?
－什么 －你能仔細聽我說嗎
- Sorry? - Can you listen, please?
你知道多少
How much do you know?
你到底有沒有聽我說話
Sorry, are you hearing me?
我只知道我被調職了
I only know I'm reassigned.
好吧
Right.
該死
Fuck.
目前的情況是我們遇到一個麻煩
Well, the situation is, we have a problem.
－也就是孢子 －孢子
- Namely, spores. - Spores.
－孢子 －黑色葡萄狀穗霉
- Spores? - Stachybotrys atra.
－霉菌毒素 －非常危險的過敏原
- Mycotoxins. - Quite dangerous allergens.
是首相發現的
The Chancellor spotted them.
她以前做過醫生 記得嗎
She was a physician herself once, remember?
－這讓我們十分憂慮 －沒錯
- But it's a very serious concern. - Very much so.
但是毋庸置疑 我們正在控制這個問題
But we're containing the problem, of course.
對 不對
Yes. Yeah. Well, no...
我們只是在努力控制問題
We're working on containing the problem as such.
所以我們要翻新首相府 拆掉內飾
Hence the renovation of the Palace.
徹底清理干凈
Tearing out the guts scraping it clean, so on.
但你能明白問題的嚴重性
But you understand the gravity of the problem,
對吧 祖巴克下士
Corporal Zubak, yes?
你明白這對首相來說是個大問題嗎
And you comprehend that the problem is real for the Chancellor?
她有危險
She's in danger?
相當危險
Well, quite great danger, yes.
但是沒關系 我們正在解決問題
But, no, we're sorting it.
你要和首相見一面 準備好了嗎
So you'll have a chat with the Chancellor, yes? Ready?
－現在嗎 －沒錯
- Now? - Now, yes.
很好 那就開始吧
Good. Come on, then.
千萬不要朝她的方向呼吸
Never breathe in her direction.
保持冷靜
Stay calm.
不要嘔吐
Don't vomit.
進來
Enter.
首相女士 這是祖巴克下士
Corporal Zubak, Madam Chancellor.
知道了
Yes.
謝謝你 蘇珊
Thank you, Susan.
抱歉 這是必要的安全措施
Sorry for all the security measures.
－你沒事吧 －沒事 首長
Are you all right? Yes, Chief.
真的沒事嗎
Are you sure?
為了我的安危 他們還真是煞費苦心
They can be so overcautious on my behalf.
別管這些人 他們只是在做準備
And don't worry about these people. They're just setting up.
－聽說你來自韋斯特蓋特 －是的 首長
So you're from Westgate, I hear. Yes, Chief.
甜菜之鄉 美不勝收
Land of the sugar beet. Stunning place.
過獎了 首長
Not so much, Chief.
你的父母呢
And your parents?
都過世了
They are dead.
我的也是 你們先退下
Mine too. Leave us.
坐
Sit.
我不想顯得太唐突
Now, I don't wish to be indelicate
但你知道我為何選你擔此重任嗎
but do you know why I selected you for this job?
不知道 首長
No, Chief.
我想要一名來自五號礦井的軍人
I wanted a Site Five boy.
不必羞愧
No, no, don't be ashamed.
那些抗議者就像野獸一樣
They behaved like animals, those protesters.
你們軍人只是做出了本能反應
You soldiers just reacted.
不管批評我的人怎么說
I was right to send you boys down that mine
我派你們去那個礦井是對的
in spite of what my critics say.
他們稱呼你們的方式太過分了 五號礦井屠夫
Not nice what they're calling you. Butchers of Site Five.
但是沒關系 我知道真相
But it's all right. I know the truth.
礦井里有個好人值得被愛
There's a good man in there who deserves love.
謝謝首長
Thank you, Chief.
你知道最奇怪的是什么嗎 我覺得我們見過
D'you know it's the oddest thing? I feel like we've met before.
有點似曾相識的感覺
A déjà vu thing or something.
或者我們在夢里見過
Or like we met in a dream.
有嗎
Have we?
應該沒有 首長
I don't think so, Chief.
他們為你解釋過工作內容吧
So, they've explained the job, then?
沒有 首長
No, Chief.
好吧
Well, fine.
沒有最好
Better they haven't.
相信我 所謂的專家 還不如我們普通人知道得多 起來
Trust me, the so-called experts know less than the common shits like us. Up.
這是液體比重計 可以測量空氣的濕度
Right. This is a hygrometer. It measures humidity in the air.
它能幫你判斷附近是否有霉菌
It helps you to tell me if there's mold nearby.
你要貼身隨行 幫我測量空氣濕度 明白嗎
We'll need you to follow me everywhere and take measurements, do you understand?
－明白 首長 －很好
- Yes, I think so, Chief. - Good.
我覺得我們很合適 你說呢
I'd say we're just about meant for each other wouldn't you?
你可以走了
Let's have you leave now.
謝謝 首長
Thank you.
下士……
Now, Corporal...
做人要有風度
a graceful mind.
你必須努力保持你的風度
You must strive to have a graceful mind.
我會努力的 首長
Yes, I will try, Chief.
謝謝
Thank you.
好
Yeah.
很好 應該沒有別的事了
Good. That should be all then.
不 我們從來不握手
Oh, no... We don't do that.
而且你必須強烈勸阻任何人
In fact, you must quite strongly dissuade anyone
用手接觸首相
from hand contact with the Chancellor.
明白嗎
Do you understand?
這一點非常重要
This is very important.
祝你工作順利 屠夫
Well, lucky fucking break, Butcher.
我們走
Let's go.
他們說清理首相府可能需要幾年時間
They say cleansin' the Palace may take years.
老天爺
God help us.
我們到了
Well, here we are.
這是你的新家
Your new home.
你明天一早就上班
You'll start first thing in the morning.
今晚你要記住 首相府的平面圖和明天的日程
Tonight, you'll memorize the floor plan and a schedule for tomorrow.
我們會派人去取你的行李
I'll have someone get your things.
你有行李嗎
Have you got things?
你聽著
Hey, you.
這些年來 我一直在打理這個破地方 別把它弄臟了
I've cared for this slag heap my whole life so don't go soilin' it.
買點保濕霜吧
And invest in some moisturizer
畢竟除濕劑會讓你的皮膚 變得像木乃伊的屁眼那么干
'cause the dehumidifiers turn your skin to a mummy's asshole.
夢里見
首相向全國發表講話
七年前的明天
Seven years ago tomorrow
我們在一場自由公正的選舉中 擊敗了愛德華凱普林格首相
we defeated Chancellor Edward Keplinger and his bandit radicals
和他那群強盜式的激進分子
in a free and fair election.
我們慶祝的是那場勝利
It is this victory that we celebrate.
當初我懷著沉重的心情 坐上了首相之位
When I became your Chancellor I did so with a heavy heart.
我知道改變這個國家千瘡百孔的模樣
I knew the hard work of smashing the failed state
會耗盡我的時間
would devour my time
會阻止我去你們身邊
and would prevent me from being next to you
握住你們的手
with your hand in mine.
但是 你們給了我無窮無盡的愛
But just know you fill me with all the love I'll ever need.
所以 我祝福你們所有人
And so, I bless you all.
也祝福我們的愛
And I bless our love,
直到永遠
always.
歐洲
政        權
第一季 第一集
本WEB版外掛字幕由  風吹來的那片云  雙語合并
喂
Hello?
起床吧
Get up.
你有20分鐘
You have 20 minutes.
勝利日快樂 屠夫
Happy Victory Day, Butcher.
勝利日快樂 赫比
Happy Victory Day, Herbie.
走吧
Let's go.
－你記住平面圖了嗎 －應該是吧
- Did you get the floor plan down? - I think so, yes.
她討厭沒把握的態度
She hates doubt.
混蛋 你要地圖嗎 去找你的組員
Do you need a mop, you prick? Go and find your section crew.
說到呼吸 她經過你身邊時你憋氣 她跟你說話時你捂嘴
Breathing. If she passes ya, hold it in. If she talks to you, cover your mouth.
多吃口香糖
Hit your mints often.
如果她聞到了霉味 你就說你也聞到了
If she smells mold tell her you smell it too.
她怎么樣
How'd she do?
她說這根香腸像狒狒的老二
She said the sausage looked like a baboon's cock.
讓廚師們吃掉嗎
Mind if the cooks eat it?
好吧 別讓守衛看到
Fine, yeah. Don't let the guards see.
她的心情如何
What's her mood?
十分里面打五分吧
Five out of ten.
十分是好的意思嗎
With a ten being good?
反正是五分 還分什么好壞
Does it matter if it's five?
來吧 靠墻站好
Come and stand against this wall.
來
Come on.
嘿
Hey,
任務很簡單
it's dead simple.
你和她一起走 然后測量相對濕度
You walk with her and you measure the relative humidity.
這個數字是什么意思
What does this number mean?
意思是別問了 機靈點
It means, Don't ask questions and look sharp
否則你的下場會和上一個一樣
or you'll end up like the last one.
打開門 走在我前面
Open the door and walk in front of me.
－情況如何 －非常好 首長
- How are we? - Very good, Chief.
不 親愛的 我問的是濕度如何
No, my dear. How's our moisture?
百分之31
It's 31%.
先去玻璃溫室 和安全局局長拉斯金先生見一面
Glasshouse first with Mr. Laskin Head of Security Service.
今天 你會喝到一鍋屎湯
Today, you'll encounter a soup tureen of worms
名為官僚主義
known as the bureaucracy.
做好準備
Prepare yourself.
勝利日快樂 首相女士
Happy Victory Day, Madam.
百分之41
It's 41%.
在這個美好的清晨 我要向您匯報情報了
Here's our intelligence on this glorious morning.
我在規劃辦公室的線人
My sources in the planning office suspect
懷疑財政部長戈恩已經等不及
Finance Minister Goin's patience is running thin
想讓您跟美國完成鈷礦合作了
waiting for you to finalize the cobalt partnership with the US.
如果您選擇繼續交易
Should you choose to proceed with the deal
我聽說美國人因為五號礦井的鬧劇
I'm told the Americans may require additional reassurance
可能需要額外的保證
due to the Site Five unseemliness.
我來說說府內的情報吧
On Palace intel, then.
樓下有人在議論您的胃口
Some chatter downstairs about your appetite.
對了 提醒您一下
And... Oh, a reminder.
您丈夫今天要接受《時尚》雜志采訪
Your husband's sitting with Vogue today.
我們是不是該監視一下
I assume we should surveil?
女士
Madam.
今天感覺好點了嗎
Feeling better today?
是的 首長
Yes, Chief.
你更有風度了
Your mind is more graceful?
應該是吧
I think so, yes.
我們昨晚在哪里來著
I wonder, where were we last night?
什么
I'm sorry?
我們見面的地方在哪里
That place we met, where was it?
昨晚
Last night?
對 親愛的 在夢里
Yes, my love. Our dream.
你不記得了嗎
Don't you remember?
甜菜
Sugar beets.
對 沒錯
Yes, that's right.
甜菜
Sugar beets.
很漂亮吧
Lovely, weren't they?
她正在上樓
She's on her way up.
禮服呢
Dress?
綠色的
Green.
非得是綠色嗎
Had to be green, didn't it?
你竟然害怕布料染劑
Are you scared of a fabric dye?
施夫先生 你真是個窩囊廢
You really are a mewling vulva, Mr. Schiff.
不然呢
Well, what do you expect?
這幾個月來 她連看都不看我一眼
She hasn't so much as glanced at me in months.
那是你的福氣
Well, consider yourself fortunate.
畢竟位高權重的人首當其沖
The right hand gets the smack.
你有沒有發現她最近冷落了
You notice how she's cooling on her favorite
她最愛的縮減GDP部長
Our Lady of the Shrinking GDP?
嫉妒會滋生自我懷疑 辛格先生
Jealousy is bred in self-doubt, Mr. Singer.
天哪
好吧 開始了
他像一只使用計算器的狗
It's like a dog using a calculator.
請她進來 屠夫
Well, see her in, Butcher.
口香糖 各位 呼吸短促點 閉上嘴
Mints, everyone. Short breaths. Mouths closed.
勝利日快樂 首相女士
Happy Victory Day, Madam.
Happy Victory Day, Ma'am.
勝利日快樂 首相女士
Happy Victory Day, Madam.
我們快點開始吧
Let's get on with it, please, yes?
這些簡報應該更簡短一些
These need to be briefer, these briefings.
令人陶醉
Oh, ravishing.
我是說 這束鮮花令人陶醉
I... I mean, the flowers are... ravishing.
沒錯
Right. Yes.
先討論德克薩斯人吧
So, the Texans.
－拜康公司 －對
- BioCon. - Yes.
首席執行官理查德凱澤今晚將攜妻子
Richard Kaiser, the CEO will be at your table tonight with his wife.
與您同桌共進晚餐
And as you know
如您所知
it would be ideal
如果能著手完成鈷礦交易 那就完美了
if we could move towards closing the cobalt deal.
你認為我在拖延時間
You think I'm dragging my heels.
－是嗎 蘇珊 －不 首相女士 當然不是
Is that it, Susan? No, no, Madam. No, of course not.
－你就是這么想的 直說吧 －女士 您也知道
Well, you do think it. Say it plainly. Well, as you know, Madam,
我們急需投資
we are in dire need of investment
而且我不說您也知道 您曾經完全贊成這筆交易
and well... Well, I needn't remind you that you once fully endorsed this deal.
或許我改變主意了
Well, perhaps my thinking's changed, hm?
你沒意見吧 你的小腦瓜不會介意吧
Is that all right with you? It doesn't tread on your little tootsies, does it?
不會 但隨著經濟指數放緩 我們的確需要找其他……
No, but with our economic indices slowing we do need to find some other...
又是該死的政治形象 我可不是什么情婦
It's the fucking optics. Like I'm a fucking kept woman.
干不出把鈷礦開采權 授予外國強國的勾當
Granting cobalt mining rights to a foreign power.
－那顯得太弱勢 －沒錯 女士
I look fucking weak. I agree, Ma'am.
我們一直在宣揚 國家要實現更大程度的自給自足
We've always messaged greater national self-sufficiency
讓美國將我們的資源 用在他們的特斯拉和筆記本電腦上
and letting America use our resources for their Teslas and laptops
與目標背道而馳 對吧
well, it's hardly that, now is it?
我尊重辛格先生 在宣傳方面的專業知識
With respect to Mr. Singer's comms expertise
但人民想要增長
the people want growth.
蘇珊 你居然知道人民的需求
And you know what the people want, do you, Susan?
你在你的鄉間別墅里 能聽到他們哼哼嗎
You can hear them grunting from your country house?
女士 拋開事實和數據
Madam, set aside the facts and figures.
真正的問題是 我們越早完成這筆交易
The real issue is the sooner we close this deal
就能越早投入到最重要的事上
the sooner we can truly invest in our top priorities.
比如保證首相府的安全
Like making this palace safe
保證您周圍的空氣安全
making the air around you safe
保證您的安全
making you safe.
對
Yes.
好吧
Well...
我看情況決定吧
let's see what happens.
你走前面 快到我前面去
In front. Front, front, in front of me now.
不要太近 保持距離
Not too close. Keep your distance.
進去就要小心了
Be careful in here.
別讓他的爪子到處亂伸
Make sure he keeps his paws to himself.
濕度
Moisture.
百分之21
21%.
收下吧
Here.
約瑟夫彼得維納姆
Trite flowers for Victory Day.
慶祝勝利日的艷俗鮮花
看 爸爸
Look, Daddy
你可能覺得我舉辦慶祝會特別傻
I'm not going to feel foolish for having a celebration
但我不會那么想
if that's what you're thinking.
我知道你一直討厭宴會 但我不討厭 所以沒關系
I know you always hated parties, but I don't so... fine.
而且每個女孩都喜歡 找個借口打扮一番
And every girl likes an excuse to dress up.
人民都愛這場慶祝會
They love it out there.
他們也愛我
Yes, they love me
遠遠超過了他們愛你的程度
much more than they ever loved you.
也許這就是我坐上了首相的位子
Yeah. Perhaps that's why I won the Chancellorship
而你還差得遠的原因吧
and you never came near it.
你想過嗎
Ever thought of that?
真是個蠢老頭
Some silly old husk.
你長斑了
You've got spots now.
真是新鮮
That's new.
你居然要有新面貌了
Leopard changing its spots.
聽得懂嗎 非常幽默
Get it? Very funny.
笑死人了
Hilarious. Right.
這樣就好了吧
Is that it? Are we done? Yes?
很好
Good.
祝你快樂
Happy, happy.
請再深呼吸一次
One more deep breath, please.
這周的情況更嚴重了
Oh, no, dear. It's worse this week.
濕度又上升了 我就知道會這樣
Humidity's spiking again. I knew it.
－放松點 女士 －我就知道會這樣
- Try and relax, Madam. - No, I knew it. I knew it.
我沒法放松 到處都是霉菌
I can't relax, can I? When there's mold everywhere.
女士 您也知道
Madam, as you are aware,
您從您父親那里 遺傳的抗胰蛋白酶缺乏癥
with the AAT deficiency that you've inherited from your father
增加了您罹患肺病的風險
you are at high risk of lung disease.
但我向您保證 我們正在盡一切努力……
But I can assure you, we are doing everything in...
還不夠
Not enough.
我還是能聞到每個房間里的腐爛氣味
I can still smell rotten air in every fucking room!
－我的藥 －等一會
- My pills, my pills! - Later.
等到宴會之前再吃
Before the banquet.
氧氣是百分之90 開啟壓力
Oxygen at 90%, under pressure.
開大點
Crank it up!
我們熱愛這本雜志 也熱愛美國
We love the magazine, of course and we love America.
我們的關系一直很緊密
Always been a very strong bond there.
那是肯定的
Oh, absolutely.
我本身是法國人 但是埃琳娜在哪 我的家就在哪
I'm French myself although my home is wherever Elena is.
不過 我們總是很樂意 和我們的北約朋友合作
But we're always happy to partner with our NATO friends
他們和我們一樣熱愛自由
who share our love of freedom.
－對 我們可以談談自由嗎 －當然
Right, the subject of freedom? By all means.
國際特赦組織稱您妻子的政府
Amnesty International says your wife's government conducts
對普通公民 進行高強度的物理和電子監控
intensive physical and electronic surveillance of private citizens.
這不是時尚雜志該問的問題吧
Sounds a bit chewy for a fashion mag, huh?
他們說的是真的
No, no. It's true.
我們確實高度重視 虛假信息四處傳播的問題
We do take very seriously the spread of disinformation.
從這個意義上說……
So in that sense.
－對 但是…… －但是談不上監視
- Right but in terms of the... - But surveillance?
絕對算不上
No. God, no.
但您承認有一些密切觀察吧
But you admit there is some close observation.
你們國家也有啊
As there is in your country.
但是
But no.
真正的民主不是一夜之間建立的
True democracy doesn't happen overnight.
我們現在比以往任何時候 都更接近民主
And we are closer now than we've ever been.
關于礦井動蕩的報道呢
And as for the reports of unrest in the... in the mines?
對 五號礦井的麻煩
- Oh, yes. - The Site Five trouble.
那只是一起獨立事件
That was an isolated incident.
一座的鈷礦出了點棘手的意外
A single cobalt mine where things got a little peppery.
但是請允許我
But if I may
把話題轉回我的國家詩歌非政府組織
I would like to steer us back to my national poetry NGO
它……
which with...
你在讓小人打架嗎 親愛的
You're making them fight, sweetheart?
－是的 －很好
- Yes. - Good.
進來
Enter.
這是勝利日晚宴的前菜 女士
The entrée for the Victory dinner, Ma'am.
就這樣吧 謝謝
We're done, thank you.
不要三文魚 沒什么味道
No... No salmon. No, salmon's meek. No.
換掉 我們需要味道濃烈的食物
No, we need robust food.
不要野味 換成羊肉
Meat, no game. Lamb.
你自己去想吧
Yeah, something.
奧斯卡 別玩了
Oh, you'll figure it out. Oskar, stop doing that.
小寶貝 跟你媽媽走 去吃你的癲癇藥
Go along with your mother now, angel and take your epilepsy pills.
我看起來怎么樣
How do I look?
完美
Perfect.
又一場宴會
Another banquet.
讓人精疲力盡
God, it's exhausting.
在這些人面前裝模作樣 為他們的笑話捧場
Wearing my face for these people smiling at their lies
啜飲清湯 我恨不能把它倒在他們頭上
slurping on consommé. I'd like to pour it on their fucking skulls.
我也想 首長
Me too, Chief.
－你想嗎 －非常想 首長
You'd like that, would you? Very much, Chief.
你今晚陪我去 好嗎
Well, you'll stick with me tonight, yeah?
監控濕度 別讓臟空氣靠近我 好嗎
Keep the humidity in check and their filthy air away from me, yes?
我任您調遣
I will do everything you want.
很好
Good.
你是個好人
You're a good man.
好孩子
Good boy.
別鬧了
Knock it off.
你在這些桌子底下都放了除濕機吧
You did put dehumidifiers under all these tables, didn't you?
是的 我的元首
Yes, Mein Führer.
等孩子睡著后 我能登門問診嗎
House call later, once the boy's asleep?
今晚不行 醫生
Not tonight, doc.
清理工作太多了
There's too much bloody clean-up.
如你所愿 小貓咪
As you like it, puss.
別再這樣叫我了
Stop calling me that.
嘿
Hey.
她到了之后 悄悄告訴她空氣濕度
When she arrives give her the number, discreetly.
如果她驚慌失措 你就護送她去那邊的走廊
And if she has a crisis escort her to that hallway there.
那里有新氧機等著她 但一定要避人耳目
There'll be fresh oxygen machines waiting but be fucking discreet.
好
Okay.
凱澤先生 埃米爾是我們國家最頂尖的商人
Mr. Kaiser, Emil's our country's top businessman.
非常可靠
You can trust him.
我們的鈷礦基礎設施 很快就會接近業界最高標準
Our cobalt pit infrastructure will soon be near top industry standards.
巴托斯先生認為 五號礦井的屠殺是業界最高標準嗎
And would Mr. Bartos call the massacre at Site Five top industry standards?
其實那是夸大其詞
Look, that was all overblown.
只是一些害群之馬
Just some bad apples.
12人死亡
Twelve deaths?
我們能加強新聞管控嗎 別讓白宮
Can we just improve the visuals, please?
在《華盛頓郵報》上 看到曠工被殺的新聞好嗎
Can we not have the White House reading about murdered pit diggers in The Washington Post?
當然可以
Of course.
說吧
So, go on, then.
－你為什么那么做 －什么
- Why did you do it? - What?
別想瞞著我 我很快就會知道的
There's no use hiding it from me. I'll find it out soon enough.
我不知道您在說什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
有人說五號礦井的礦工根本沒有暴動
Well, some say the miners at Site Five weren't rioting at all, you know?
他們只是受夠了有毒的空氣和臟水
They were fed up with the poisoned air and the dirty water
所以他們提出了意見
so they raised their voices.
而你們這些軍人 直接在慌亂之下開了槍
And you Army boys just panicked and opened fire.
不過 我想知道
I wonder, though.
你當時也慌了嗎
Did you panic
還是樂在其中
or did you enjoy it?
各位取得勝利的朋友們
My victorious friends
回想七年前 腐敗已經蔓延到國家的內部
cast your minds back seven years ago to the rot in our nation's heart.
我們曾是一群支離破碎的人
We were a broken people.
當然 我們知道 是誰把我們變成了那樣
Of course, we know who broke us.
前首相愛德華凱普林格
The former Chancellor, Edward Keplinger.
那個叛徒
The Rat
他和新馬克思主義賊黨勾結在一起
and his crony cabal of neo-Marxist thieves.
給我們帶來了絕望
He made us feel hopeless.
直到我們看到了她
That was until we saw her face.
來自林堡的年輕醫生 長著一雙明亮的眼睛
The young doctor from Rinnburg with the brilliant eyes.
她將她父親創建的小黨派 變成了一個龐然大物
She took the tiny party her father founded and transformed it into a monster.
她痛擊了凱普林格
She trounced Keplinger!
將他趕回了他的鄉下老家 如今 他還在那里舔傷呢
Ran him off to his country home where he licks his wounds still.
各位 和我一起 還有我們的美國新朋友
So, join me. All. Our new American friends, too.
敬埃琳娜維納姆
A toast to Elena Vernham.
敬首相
To the Chancellor!
很高興見到各位如此光彩照人
Wonderful to see you all looking so magnificent.
真的 我會心碎的
You will. I'll be heartbroken.
別走 我只想讓你留下
No! I just want you to stay.
我的丈夫尼基也這樣想 各位 這是尼古拉斯維納姆
And so does Nicky, my husband. Nicholas Vernham, everybody.
怎么能呢 你在我眼中珍貴無比
How could we ever? You're so precious to me.
沒錯 我們必須繼續走下去
We have. We must carry on forever.
我們怎么可能這樣結束
How could we end it all this way?
等到明天 我們都會后悔……
When tomorrow comes and we'll both regret
不要離開我
Don't you leave me now.
女士們 先生們 謝謝 非常感謝
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you. Oh, thank you so much!
看 他們真可愛
Oh, do look. That's sweet.
尼基 快看 親愛的 他們站起來了
Oh, Nicky, look. Darling, they're standing up.
天哪 我要感動哭了
Oh, god, I think I'm going to cry.
－天哪 －你看起來真美
- Goodness. - That was lovely.
－我唱得還行嗎 －很好
Is that all right?
－真的嗎 －真的
- Honestly, are you sure? - Yes, honey.
來吧 深呼吸
Now, come on, deep breaths.
太精彩了 女士
Wonderful, Madam.
謝謝 蘇珊 謝謝
Oh, thank you, thank you, Susan.
太棒了
Thank you. How wonderful.
你們好 謝謝
Hello, thank you.
－天哪 凱澤先生 －凱澤夫人
- My goodness, Mr. Kaiser. - Mrs. Kaiser.
－幸會 －不要接觸 先生
- Pleasure. - No, no touching, sir.
你讓一下……
Excuse me. Excuse me. Thanks. Now... Thank you.
真是幸會 凱澤先生
Such a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Kaiser.
還有您親愛的妻子 凱澤夫人
And your darling wife, Mrs. Kaiser.
您好
- Hello. - Charmed.
幸會 請坐
Please, let's sit. We must.
－濕度大約是百分之40 －夠了 非常感謝
- It's about 40% humidity. - That will be all. Thank you so much.
－濕度 －不
- Humidity? - No.
這只是個愚蠢的玩笑
It's just a stupid joke, really.
－我們應該帶雨衣嗎 －不用
Should we have brought raincoats? No.
真對不起 我和妻子都不吃肉
Oh, I'm so sorry. My wife and I don't eat meat,
只吃魚
only fish.
請原諒我們員工的錯誤
Oh, please forgive our staff's mistake.
您和首相是怎么認識的
How did you and the Chancellor meet?
我們在醫學院認識的
We met in medical school
在巴黎的時候
in Paris.
當時我有妻子和孩子 但埃琳娜很有說服力
I had a wife and a baby at the time but Elena is very persuasive.
我想象得到
I can imagine.
只可惜她回去追求政治了
Alas, she went home to pursue politics
所以我回到了妻子和孩子身邊
so I went back to my wife and kid.
后來她認為婚姻有助于她競選成功
And then she thought that marriage would help her campaign
所以她讓我求婚 我照做了
so she asked me to propose which I did.
我徹底離開了巴黎的家人 從此再也沒見過他們
And I left my family in Paris for good and haven't seen them since.
就這樣 我們過上了幸福的生活
And thus, here we are, happily ever after.
我們非常喜歡巴黎
Well, we do love Paris.
請恕我失陪一下
Will you excuse me for a moment, please?
我能和你談談嗎
May I speak with you?
過來 請吧 過去
Go here, please. Go, go there.
快 沒錯 快過去
Go on. Go on. That's it. Go on in there.
麻煩你看著我
Look at me, please.
你現在滿意了嗎
You happy now? Yes, are you?
他們都把我當成瘋子了
They think I'm a lunatic now.
你簡直是給他們遞刀子
You've handed them all the leverage.
你知道嗎 我一個人奔波 為我的國家謀福利
D'you know I am out there by myself hustling, providing for my country
你卻讓美國人看我的笑話
and you've made me look ridiculous in front of the Americans.
我不是笑話
I am not ridiculous.
我完全不是笑話 你這個蠢貨
I am very much not ridiculous you stupid cunt.
對不起
I'm sorry.
下次把槍對準你自己
Next time turn your gun on yourself.
塞進你嘴里 你這個不要臉的賤人
Stick it in your mouth you graceless fucking cow.
我們應該聊一聊
So... we should talk.
－但是先用餐吧 －當然
- But let's eat first, I think. - Oh, no. Sure.
我之前和您的家人聊過 但是……
I talked to a few of your folks earlier, you know...
現在不是他們了 對吧
Well, you're not talking to my folks now, are you?
您現在要和我聊
You're talking to me.
我聽說您的態度很強硬
And I heard you were playing hardball which is fine.
但是沒關系 您在擔心什么
But what are you concerned about, hm?
一點點工人動蕩
Bit of worker unrest?
搖搖晃晃的體制
Some wonky machinery, hm?
那都是細枝末節
It's marginalia.
看看我們的現狀
Look at what we are.
我們是一個年輕的中歐共和國
We are a young, Central European republic
正準備接受一家現代公司的治理
ready to embrace a modern corporate governance.
我們準備與你們一起成長
We're ready to grow, with you.
最重要的是
Here's the important part.
我們熱愛美國
We love America.
我們熱愛我們的友誼
We love our friendship.
一心想要加強與你們的聯系
And we'd love nothing more than to tighten those bonds.
我們有鈷礦
We have the cobalt.
你們支付礦坑和精煉廠的錢
You pay for the pits and the refineries.
這是完美的合作關系
It's a perfect partnership.
不然 你們就等著 中國在你們鞋上撒尿時跪舔他們吧
Or you can hold China's cock while they piss all over your shoes
被他們腐敗的供應鏈扣為人質
and hold you hostage to their corrupt supply lines.
那好吧
All right, then.
按照約定 我們將拿到采礦權股份的百分之30
30% stake in mining rights as agreed.
很好
Good.
就這么定了
Let's do that then.
但我希望您能保證我們達到51
But I would like your assurance of our ability to get to 51.
百分之51
51%.
這符合這種交易結構的慣例
Which would, of course, be... de rigueur in a deal structure like this
就是爭取多數股權
to advance to a majority stake.
一直都是這樣的 您盡管放心
Well, that's how it's always done, don't worry.
抱歉 我得先問清楚
Sorry, just to be clear
假如我想把我們的鈷礦另作他用
so if I wanted then to do something with our cobalt
還要得到你們的允許嗎
I'd have to ask your permission?
這完全不是問題
It won't be a problem.
我們會非常公正
We'll be more than fair.
別放他進來
Not him.
在這里等著
Wait here.
－我不想再看到他的臉 －是 女士
艾格尼絲保住了你的命
Agnes managed to keep you whole.
不然我就要給動物園的獅子送鮮肉了
I would've sent the zoo some fresh lion food.
你已經不是首相的私人水卜師了
So, you're no longer the Chancellor's personal water diviner.
你是宿舍樓層的夜間濕度哨兵
You are now the night moisture sentry for the residence floor.
－你知道那是什么意思嗎 －不知道
- Do you know what that means? - No.
就是說你從午夜到早上六點 都得在走廊上揮舞你那該死的小玩意
It means that you wave your fucking gizmo around these halls from midnight to 6.00am
而且你再也見不到首相了
and you never see the Chancellor's face again.
好好享受吧 屠夫
Enjoy it, Butcher.
我只是想幫忙
I was trying to help.
就像你在五號礦井幫忙一樣
Like you helped at Site Five.
別活了
Just kill yourself.
韋斯特蓋特的垃圾
Westgate trash.
別活了
Just kill yourself!
Kill... kill yourself!
沒用的東西
Useless beef.
別活了
Just kill yourself.
Kill yourself!
媽的
Fuck... Fuck!
沒事的
It's all right.
It's... it's all right.
我知道
Yes, I know.
我知道你害怕
I know you're scared.
我們兩個可以一起害怕
We can both be scared, hm?
我們會共渡難關的
Yes, we'll... we'll get through this together.
－怎么回事 －我們的立場一致
- What's going... - We come from the same place you and I
所以我們會親密無間 親愛的
and that's why we'll be thick as thieves, my love.
首長
Chief!
去死Dead...
去死
Dead!
我聞到了他的呼吸
I breathed him... I breathed him!
出去
Out... out!
我聞到了他的呼吸
I breathed him!
放在椅子上
In the chair.
－我聞到了他的呼吸 －把手給我
- I breathed him! Oh, my god! - All right, hon, give me your hands. Give me your hands.
我聞到了他的呼吸
Please! Please help me!
出去
Get out! Out!
救救我
Help me! Help me!
Help. Help me.
繼續吸
Give your arm. Give your arm.
兩周后
你來這里做什么
What are you doing here?
為了幫他們抓微生物
They needed more scrubby hands for the great microbe hunt.
小貓咪 想我了嗎
Miss me, puss?
別再這樣叫我了
Stop calling me that.
外面的人聽到什么消息了
What are people hearing outside?
只有國家新聞上的報道
Only what the state news tells them.
首相正在山里享受早就該有的假期
The Chancellor is enjoying a well-deserved holiday in the mountains.
是啊 瘋狂之山
The mountains of fucking madness.
兩周沒有公開露面 人民一定察覺到異樣了
Two weeks without a public appearance. People must know something's up.
那個男孩怎么樣了
How's the boy?
他沒事
Yeah, he's fine, yeah.
他一直在問她在哪
Keeps asking where she is.
那個老姑娘去哪了
Where is the old girl?
天知道 沒人見過她 除了……
Lord knows. Nobody's seen her except...
這個能幫您抵抗病魔
This will help your body to fight.
這是向日葵茶 跟我母親以前煮的一樣
It's sunflower, like my mother used to make.
有解毒之效
It hates poison.
先生
Sir?
我想見她
Yeah, I... I'd like to see her.
她在等您嗎
Is she expecting you?
我是她丈夫
I'm her husband.
她在等您嗎
Is she expecting you?
丈夫進入妻子的房間很正常
One expects their husband to enter a room.
沒事的 親愛的
It's all right, my love.
親愛的
My love.
你好 尼基
Hello, Nicky.
我很想你 琳妮
I've missed you, Lenny.
戈恩部長和科肖醫生 想與你分享一個短期計劃
Minister Goin and Dr. Kershaw wanted to share a plan for the short term.
和他們聊聊也無妨
Perhaps it wouldn't hurt to chat?
他長斑了
He's got spots now.
你說什么 親愛的
Sorry, dear?
越來越多的斑
More spots.
你看見了
Have you seen?
誰長斑了 親愛的
Who has, my love?
他
Him,
樓下
downstairs.
在他臉上
On his face.
已經過去一年了 親愛的
It's been a year now, my love.
這很正常
I... I'm sure it's normal.
不
No.
不是給他化妝了嗎
That's what cosmetics are for.
我不該發現那些斑的
I should not have to spot the spots.
琳妮 你是不是該放下他了
Lenny, do you suppose... maybe it's time to let him go?
別說了
Stop... Stop it.
我已經放下了 別說了
I have. Just... stop that.
你還記得
我們在哈辛大街度過的第一晚吧
你直接走到街上
所有的車都停了下來
你想吃什么就吃什么
我當時就被你迷住了
你是那么的無所畏懼
你現在依然如此 親愛的
以前的我和現在沒有區別
你只是一直沒看清真正的我
跟他們說 我中午見他們
Tell them I'll meet them at noon.
首相女士 您的氣色不錯
Madam Chancellor, you look well
希望您正在快速復原中
and we hope you're recuperating briskly.
那件事真是令人震驚
It's been quite a shock.
沒錯
Very much so.
過去幾周糟透了
Terrible, terrible few weeks.
那件事令人無法想象
What happened was unthinkable.
這純屬意外 那是個瘋子
A fluke, some lunatic.
聽說是以前的鈷礦工混進了建筑隊
A former cobalt miner turned builder, we've learned.
精神不正常
Very ill in the head.
但我們正在采取一切措施
But every measure is being taken to ensure
杜絕此類事件的發生
that nothing of this nature ever happens again.
徹底杜絕
Absolutely not.
再也不會有了
Never again.
女士 我就不拐彎抹角了
Madam there's no use dancing around it.
現在的首相府根本不適合您居住
The Palace, at present, is simply unfit for your habitation.
數據是無可辯駁的
The data is incontrovertible.
我們目前的窘境是
Here's the bind.
我們不能再經歷一次安全漏洞了
We can't risk further security breaches
所以翻新工作必須暫停
and so the renovation has to be put on hold.
必須暫停
No question.
當然 這就意味著……
Which means, of course...
您在墻內檢測到的毒素無法去除
The toxicity you detected in the walls would remain.
這里會變成一個培養皿
You'd be trapped in a petri dish.
所以您只能遷往郊區
Meaning a relocation of sorts to the countryside
這個建議正在等待您的批準
pending your approval.
當然 在您康復期間
Of course, while you recuperate
某些政府職能仍需要在這里運作
certain government functions would still need to operate here.
所以我和一些特定的工作人員
And so, myself and a select staff
將留在這里監督這些職能
would remain in the capital to oversee those functions.
只執行重要任務 比如完成鈷礦交易
Vital tasks only, such as finishing the cobalt deal.
女士 您父親肺衰竭時 我們無能為力
Madam we weren't able to save your father from his failing lungs
但現在救您還不晚
but it's not too late to save you.
謝謝你們
Thank you both.
你們可以走了
You may go.
好好休息 女士
Rest well, Madam.
下士 坐吧
Corporal, sit.
不
No.
過來 坐我旁邊
Come here. Sit beside me.
你知道我為什么叫你來嗎
Do you know why you're here?
不知道
No.
因為你是無名小卒 明白嗎
You're here because you are nobody do you understand?
這不是侮辱 而是事實
I don't mean that as an insult. I only mean it as a fact.
你只是個無名小卒
You are not anybody.
所以我可以信任你 對嗎
And that means I can trust you, yes?
是的 首長
Yes, Chief.
現在只有你能告訴我
Now, you are the only one
無名小卒想要什么
who can tell me what the nobodies want.
看著我
Look at me.
你愛我 是不是
You love me, don't you?
－是的 －你能說出來嗎
- Yes. - Can you say it?
我愛您
I love you.
好
Yes.
如果你愛我 就老實地告訴我
Now if you love me tell me honestly
你希望接下來發生什么
what would you like to happen next?
告訴我
Tell me.
昨晚我夢到您了 而我也出現在了您的夢里
You were in my dream last night and I was in yours.
您讓我干掉一切讓您軟弱的人
And you told me to crush them anyone who makes you weak.
他們挫傷了我們的骨氣 首長
They've cut our balls off, Chief.
而且正在嘲笑我們
And now they are laughing at us
因為您像馬戲團里的病熊一樣 為外國的有錢人跳舞
because you dance for foreign cash like a sick fucking bear at the circus.
外面的人都是這么說的
And that's what everybody's saying out there.
您聽不到 但他們就是這么說的 相信我
You don't hear it, but that's what they are saying, trust me.
美國把我們當成了他們的殖民地
America treats us as if we are their fucking colony.
他們是怎么做的
So, what do they do?
他們整天往我們身上撒尿
They rain piss on us all day.
他們想讓您垮臺
They want you to fail.
您那個犯賤的財政部長也一樣
And so does your finance bitch.
還有那個說您有病的豬頭醫生
And so does your fat pig doctor telling you that you are sick.
您病了 一派胡言
You are sick? That's bullshit!
有些東西是真的
Something, yes, it's true.
這棟建筑里確實有東西會害死您
Something in this building is killing you
但不是這鬼東西
but it's not this shit.
不是這個鬼東西
It's not this shit.
是他們
It's them!
他們希望您 看著我
They want you... Look at me.
他們希望您變成殘廢
They want you crippled
因為您有他們永遠沒有的東西
because you have something they will never, ever have.
一個該死的夢想
A fucking dream.
我想徹底打爛他們的臉
I'd love to smash their fucking faces forever.
做人要有風度
A graceful mind.
一 二 三 四 拇指大戰開始啦
One, two, three, four. I declare a thumb war.
用力
Fight...
不是吧 你用戰術了
No... That's a tactic!
你用戰術了
That was a tactic!
尼基 你看到了嗎
Nicky, did you see that? Let's try again.
我們再試一次 看著我的眼睛 我贏定了
Look me in the eye. I'm about to win.
一 二 三 四 拇指大戰開始啦
One, two, three, four. I declare a thumb war.
用力
Fight. Fight!
我贏了
Got you!
好吧 三局兩勝
Okay, best of three.
一 二 三 四 用力
One, two, three, four.
不
Fight...
你太壞了
No, no. You are terrible!
朋友們
My friends
幾周前 我國政府的一位高級部長
a few weeks ago, one of my government's top ministers
和我府上的重要隨從
along with key members of my household retinue
勾結有外國勢力支持的間諜
conspired with a foreign-backed fifth column
趁我熟睡時行刺我
to assassinate me while I slept.
放開我
Sir, get off me! Get off me!
在過去的一年里 這些人在外國政權的幫助下
For the past year these individuals have weakened our economy
削弱了我們的經濟 政府 甚至還有我的免疫系統
our government and even my immune system aided by meddling foreign regimes.
因此我要在今天發布一項行政命令 償還我們的債務
Which is why today I am issuing an executive order to repay our debts
拒絕美國投資者
turn away American investors
讓這個國家擺脫 對北約乳頭的病態依賴
and rid this country of its sick dependence on NATO's teat.
全國各地的民眾在本周展示的
My husband and I have been deeply touched by the outpouring
源源不斷的愛和支持 讓我和我丈夫深受感動
of love and support we've seen across the nation this week.
這才是我們人民真正的精神
This is the true spirit of our people.
你們是跳動的心臟
You are the beating heart.
你們是萬物的靈魂
You are the soul of everything.
你們是我汲取力量 擊敗敵人的堅強后盾
You are the well from which I draw strength to vanquish our enemies.
我不會讓你們卷入美國
I will not let you be sucked into the decadence and toxicity of America
及其同黨的墮落和毒害之中
and its surrogates around the globe.
多年來 我們飽受折磨
For years, we have suffered
好讓他們按照自己的形象 建立全球秩序
so they could build the global order in their image.
他們為國外的腐敗政權提供物質援助
They've provided material aid to corrupt regimes abroad.
他們犯下了 并教唆別人犯下了大屠殺
They committed and abetted mass murder
他們在地球的每個角落
and they've waged their crony capitalist war
發動了裙帶資本主義戰爭
in every corner of the planet.
還告訴其他國家
They have told the rest of us
好好合作 坐直了 聽我們指揮 買路錢自付
Play ball. Sit up straight do as we tell you, and pay the toll.
是時候喊停了
It's time to say enough.
我們不會再參與他們的殘暴行徑
We will no longer be a party to their legacy of brutality.
我們不會再為他們的貪婪受罪
We will no longer suffer for their greed.
是時候向美國和全世界 展示我們的價值了
It is time to show America and the world precisely what we are worth.
我祝福你們所有人 也祝福我們的愛 直到永遠
I bless you all. And I bless our love, always.
待續
謝謝觀賞